kendall.edu 2007-12-03

# ADA and Privacy Policies

  * KENDALL COLLEGE’S AMERICANS WITH DISABILITIES ACT (ADA) POLICY

  * KENDALL COLLEGE'S PRIVACY POLICY

 **

* * *

**

###### **KENDALL ** COLLEGE** **’S AMERICANS WITH DISABILITIES ACT (ADA) POLICY****

These guidelines promulgate policies and procedures that students of Kendall College should follow when seeking disability accommodations, and/or when disputing decisions that Kendall makes in response to accommodation requests. These guidelines are designed to comply with the disability accommodation requirements of the federal Rehabilitation Act of 1973 and the Americans with Disabilities Act (“ADA”) of 1990. For more information about Kendall’s disability accommodation policies, see the school’s Academic Success Center (“ASC”). 

**I. GENERAL PROVISIONS**

Kendall does not discriminate on the basis of disability in any of its programs, services or activities. The school will not deny any otherwise qualified student with a disability the opportunity to participate in, or benefit from, any aid, benefit or service that Kendall provides. Kendall will also strive to accommodate applicants and students with disabilities on an individual basis. 

While Kendall College strives to accommodate students as fully as possible, reasonable adjustments or accommodations do not include measures which fundamentally alter the academic programs of Kendall College, or which place an undue financial burden on the school. The College will, however, engage in a good-faith interactive process with all disabled students to attempt to identify reasonable, mutually-acceptable disability accommodations.

**II. REQUESTING ACCOMMODATIONS**

Students requiring accommodations must first provide professional verification of the condition(s) that necessitate the accommodations.

Students with physical disabilities must provide verification by a licensed health care provider who is qualified to diagnose the disability being claimed. Verification may be made by forms available at the ASC (i.e., the ASC will provide the forms to the students who will then have the forms filled out by their respective medical providers). The verification must indicate how the student is limited by his or her disability (e.g., cannot sit for periods longer than 30 minutes, cannot see or hear beyond certain distances, etc.), and how long the limitation(s) is/are expected to last. The student shall provide the verification documentation to the ASC. The ASC may ask the student to provide additional verification if the initial verification the student provides is incomplete or inadequate to determine the need for accommodations.

Students with learning disabilities must provide professional testing and evaluation results which reflect the students’ present levels of achievement and information processing. The ASC can provide more information about eligibility for learning disability adjustments or accommodations, as well as documentation criteria. The cost of obtaining professional verification of a learning disability shall be borne by the student.

**III. GRANTING ACCOMMODATIONS**

The ASC will review all documents submitted to verify a disability and will conduct a personal interview to explore the particular needs of the student requesting an accommodation. The student may be asked to submit a history, if any, of academic adjustments and/or accommodations received in secondary or post-secondary institutions, or in places of employment. Such a history of adjustments and/or accommodations will be subject to verification by the institution or place of employment that facilitated the adjustments or accommodations. 

After considering the verification documents, the results of the personal interview, and the history of academic adjustments and accommodations, the ASC will devise a schedule of academic adjustments and/or accommodations appropriate for the individual student. The student shall be notified, in writing, of the ASC’s accommodation decision promptly after it has been made. Unless the student challenges the decision subject to the provisions of Section IV below, the ASC’s accommodation decision will be implemented as soon as is practicable. Every student who receives accommodations and/or academic adjustments shall meet upon request with the ASC to evaluate the effectiveness of the accommodations and/or adjustments in place. Each student shall immediately report any dissatisfaction with an accommodation or academic adjustment to the ASC. Kendall faculty and staff will be informed of qualifying students’ accommodations and/or academic adjustments on a need-to-know basis. ****

**IV. CHALLENGING ACCOMMODATION DECISION**

If a student does not feel that an accommodation decision will adequately address the student’s disability, then the student should contact the Vice President of Academic Affairs. After reviewing the case, the Vice President of Academic Affairs will make a determination about what accommodation(s) will be offered to the student. Accommodation decisions by the Vice President of Academic Affairs are final. 

##### **KENDALL COLLEGE'S PRIVACY POLICY**

Privacy is extremely important to us. Please read the following to understand our views and practices regarding this matter and how they pertain to you. Kendall College gathers several types of information about our visitors: data that prospective students provide when inquiring about academic programs, information about how many people visit our site, and personal contact information supplied by visitors signing up for services provided and transmitted by Kendall College or other promotions such as our dining services, courses and various surveys. Such information enables us to better tailor our products/services to our visitors' needs and to help us better understand the demographics of our visitors. Kendall College may from time to time use contractors to help it deliver its educational programs. NEITHER KENDALL COLLEGE NOR ANY OF ITS CONTRACTORS SHARES INFORMATION ABOUT INDIVIDUAL VISITORS WITH ANY OTHER PARTY. Kendall College gathers user information in the following processes: Electronic newsletter - Kendall College offers a free e-mail newsletter to visitors. Kendall College gathers the e-mail addresses of visitors who voluntarily subscribe. Customers may remove themselves from this mailing list by following the instructions included in every newsletter. Usage tracking - Kendall College tracks visitor traffic patterns throughout our site. However, we do not correlate this information with data about individual visitors. Kendall College may/does break down overall usage statistics according to a visitor's domain name, browser type, and MIME type using the information supplied by the user's Web browser, such as IP address, browser type, version and platform.

Kendall College does not share mailing lists or personal information supplied with any third parties, including advertisers, constituencies or partners except as necessary for the purposes of marketing, delivering, and evaluating our own programs. We use tracking information to determine which areas of our site visitors like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. Kendall College does not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. Kendall College uses the information described above to tailor our products and content to suit your needs and help us better understand our audience's demographics. Kendall College will not disclose any of your personal information, except as described above, or when we believe in good faith that the law requires it, or to protect the rights or property of Kendall College. Kendall College does disclose aggregated user statistics in order to describe our services to prospective constituencies, partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes. Virtual Postcards- When you send one of our virtual postcards, the information you provide to us is used to customize your greeting with the recipient's name and with your message, and to deliver an email notification to the recipient. We treat our cards as private correspondence between the sender and the recipient and will not disclose the contents of a card, other than to the intended recipient, unless we are required to do so by law or we in good faith believe that such action is necessary to (1) comply with the law or with legal process; (2) protect and defend our rights and property; (3) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of Kendall College; or (4) protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public. However, if you provide a false email address or attempt to pose as someone else when sending information about you - including your computer's IP address - may be disclosed as part of any investigation into your actions. 

Kendall College uses reasonable precautions to keep the personal information disclosed to us secure and to disclose such information where appropriate only to third parties we believe to be responsible. However, we are not responsible for any breach of security or for any actions of any third parties which receive the information. Kendall College also links to a wide variety of other sites. We are not responsible for their privacy policies or how they treat information about their users.
